<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="agl_shell_desktop">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2020 Collabora, Ltd.

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>
  <interface name="agl_shell_desktop" version="1">
    <description summary="Private extension to allow applications activate other apps">
      This extension can be used by regular application to instruct to compositor
      to activate or switch to other running (regular) applications. The client
      is responsbile for filtering their own app_id when receiving application id.

      Note that other (regular) applications can bind to this interface and there is
      no mechanism to place to restrict or limit that.
    </description>

    <enum name="app_role">
      <entry name="popup" value="0"/>
      <entry name="fullscreen" value="1"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="app_state">
      <entry name="activated" value="0"/>
      <entry name="deactivated" value="1"/>
    </enum>

    <event name="application">
      <description summary="advertise application id">
        The compositor may choose to advertise one or more application ids which
        can be used to activate/switch to.

        When this global is bound, the compositor will send all application ids
        available for activation, but may send additional application id at any
        time (when they've been mapped in the compositor).
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
    </event>

    <request name="activate_app">
      <description summary="make client current window">
        Ask the compositor to make a toplevel to become the current/focused
        window for window management purposes.

        See xdg_toplevel.set_app_id from the xdg-shell protocol for a
        description of app_id.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
      <arg name="app_data" type="string" allow-null="true"/>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_app_property">
      <description summary="set properties for a client identified by app_id">
        Ask the compositor to make a toplevel obey the app_role and, depending
        on the role, to use the the x and y values as initial positional values.
        The x and y values would only make sense for certain roles.

        See xdg_toplevel.set_app_id from the xdg-shell protocol for a
        description of app_id.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
      <arg name="role" type="uint" enum="app_role"/>
      <arg name="x" type="int"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int"/>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output"/>
    </request>

    <request name="deactivate_app">
      <description summary="de-activate/hide window identified by app_id">
        Ask the compositor to hide the toplevel window for window
        management purposes. Depending on the window role, this request
        will either display the previously active window (or the background
        in case there's no previously activate surface) or temporarly (or
        until a 'activate_app' is called upon) hide the surface. All
        the surfaces are identifiable by using the app_id, and no actions are
        taken in case the app_id is not/was not present.

        See xdg_toplevel.set_app_id from the xdg-shell protocol for a
        description of app_id.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
    </request>

    <event name="state_app">
      <description summary="event sent when application has suffered state modification">
        Notifies application(s) when other application have suffered state modifications.
      </description>
      <arg name="app_id" type="string"/>
      <arg name="app_data" type="string" allow-null="true"/>
      <arg name="state" type="uint" enum="app_state"/>
      <arg name="role" type="uint" enum="app_role"/>
    </event>

  </interface>
</protocol>
